(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T12:43:49.278524",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
born to be real
例えば 泣いてたら
Whether you're crying
例えば 笑ってたら
or laughing,
何事も無く済んだんだ
saying everything was fine,
自分に嘘をついて
you're just lying to yourself,
虚勢ばかり一人前で
putting up a bold front.
形振り構わずなんて
Careless of how you look,
感情にシラを切って
feigning ignorance of your feelings,
何を守んんだろう
what are you protecting?
永遠に愛したって
To love eternally,
期待したって違うんでしょ
to have expectations—it's not right.
一体誰にとっての天使だろう
Whose angel are you trying to be?
何も言わないで
Don't say anything,
消さないで もう止まらないから
don't erase it, it can't be stopped.
大切な人にはきっと
I'm sure to the ones you cherish
この声が届くはず
this voice will surely reach them.
born to be real
たとえば泣いてたら 例えば笑ってたら
Whether you're crying or laughing,
何事も無く済んだんだ
saying everything is fine,
自分に嘘をついて
you're just lying to yourself.
虚勢ばっか一人前で形振り構わずなんて
Just putting up a bluff and acting all tough,
感情にシラを切って何を守んだろう
ignoring your emotions, what are you protecting?
born to be on stage
永遠に愛したって
to love eternally,
期待したって違うんでしょう
to have expectations, it's not right, is it?
一体誰にとっての天使だろう
Whose angel could you possibly be?
何も言わないで消さないで もう止まらないから
Don't say anything, don't erase it, it can't be stopped.
大切な人にはきっとこの声が届くはず
I'm sure this voice will reach the ones I cherish.
born to be real
簡単に投げられた言葉 その意味も恐さも知らないなんて
Words thrown out so easily, knowing neither meaning nor fear,
堪んねえな
I can't stand this!
虚勢ばっか一人前で正論咬ましたつもりで
Putting up a bluff and acting all righteous,
その正義の反対は別の正義じゃないの
is the opposite of that justice another justice?
hey please answer 分からないよ誰か教えて
Hey please answer, I don't get it, someone tell me!
永遠に愛したって期待したって
To love eternally, to have expectations,
違うんでしょう 一体何をもっての正解だろう
it's not right, is it? What makes it the right answer?
何も言えないよ分からないよだから歌うんだ
I can't say anything, I don't understand, so I'll sing.
誰かじゃなくキミの為にこの声が枯れるまで
Not for anyone else, but for you, until my voice goes hoarse,
born to be real
生まれた理由だって意味だってきっと後付けなんだ
The reason and meaning of birth are surely afterthoughts,
だけど出会えたそれが全てなんだ
but meeting you is everything.
例えば泣いてたって笑ってってたって変わんない未来
Whether crying or laughing, an unchanging future,
自分に今日も嘘ついて
I'm lying to myself again today.
何をどうしたって塞いだってもどうせ同じなら
No matter what I do, if it's all the same anyway,
嘘つきは yameta んだ
I'm done being a liar!
永遠に愛したって期待したって違うんでしょう
To love eternally, to have expectations, it's not right, is it?
一体誰にとっての天使だろう
Whose angel could you possibly be?
何も言わないで消さないで もう止まらないから
Don't say anything, don't erase it, it can't be stopped.
大切な人にはきっとこの声が届くはず
I'm sure this voice will reach the ones I cherish.
born to be real
イェーイ！ということでみんなこんばんは！ホロ...じゃなくて朝まで！朝までだー！
Yeah! Good evening everyone! Holo... No, till morning! Till morning!
はい！ということでこの広いステージに今トワ一人！
Right! So right now Towa is all alone on this huge stage!
そして先ほど撮ったのはサードフェスぶりだね！「Palette」というトワのオリジナル曲になります。どうだったかな？
And the one we just filmed is from the 3rd fes! It's Towa's original song "Palette". How was it?
ちょっとサードフェスとはね、若干、若干違う振りにはなってますけれども、なんでかっていうと日が空いているから。
It has slightly different choreography from the 3rd fes, and that's because some time has passed.
まあそんなことは気にしない気にしない！でも、この水ちゃんが好きなね、この振りは...
Well, don't worry about that! But, this choreography that Suisei-chan likes...
この振りはみんな、どうだったかな？いいでしょ？ハーイ！ということで、今日はね、あの常闇トワの誕生日なんです！
How was this choreography everyone? Pretty good, right? Right! So today is Tokoyami Towa's birthday!
ハッピーバースデートゥーミー！はいみんなハッピーバースデーありがとう！はい、コメントでもね、多分ね、もう早読みで、もうあ...ありがとう！ハッピーバースデーありがとね！
Happy birthday to me! Yes everyone, happy birthday, thank you! Yes, in the comments too, reading ahead... Ah, thank you! Happy birthday, thanks!
もう早読みで、もうあ、ありがとう！ハッピーバースデーありがとねー！はい、早読み完了ということで。
Reading ahead, already ah, thank you! Happy birthday thanks! Okay, reading ahead is complete.
はい、じゃあね今日のハッシュタグは、「#常闇トワ生誕祭2022」でつぶやいてください！ぜひぜひトレンドにも入りたいのでいっぱいつぶやいてくんないと...おこちゃんだぞ！
Right, so today's hashtag is "#常闇トワ生誕祭2022"! Please tweet with it! I definitely want to trend, so if you don't tweet a lot... I'll be mad!
はい、じゃあね今日の配信はなんとなんと！いつもはね、トークしたりとかちょっと話しながら歌ってライブをするんだけど、今日はもう歌をいっぱい歌いたいなと思ってるので、トークは短め！いっぱい歌うのでたくさん見てください！聞いてね！
Okay, so today's stream is, believe it or not! Usually I talk and chat a bit while singing live, but today I want to sing lots of songs, so the talk will be short! I'll be singing a lot so please watch a lot! Listen to it!
ちょっとこだわりもあるんでね、ちゃんと見ていっぱい聞いて見ていっぱい聞いていっぱい聞いていっぱい呟いてくれたら嬉しいな！はーい！では、この後はトワの好きな曲をたくさんのゲストといっぱい歌いますので聞いてください！ではゲストコーナーどうぞ！ボン！
There's also some attention to detail, so I'd be happy if you watch, listen, listen, listen, and tweet a lot! Okay! Now, after this, I'll be singing lots of my favorite songs with many guests, so please listen! Now, guest corner, go! Boom!
白銀の獅子は 駆けて駆けて 駆け続けている
The silver lioness dashes, dashes, and continues dashing.
もう不安に振り返ることはないから
Because she doesn't look back with fear anymore.
百獣の王は 九十九を信じるから王なんだ
The king of beasts is a king because she believes in the 99.
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride それこそ私の誇り
We have the pride, and it's our reason of pride—that is my pride.
白銀の獅子は 駆けて 駆けて 駆け続けている
The silver lioness runs, runs, and keeps on running
もう不安に 振り返る ことはないから
Because she no longer needs to look back with anxiety
百獣の王は 九十九を 信じるから王なんだ
The king of beasts is a king because she believes in ninety-nine
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride.
それこそ 私の誇り
That is my pride
孤高は 孤独の裏返しで
Aloofness is the flip side of solitude
ずっと 一匹なんだろうって 思ってた
I used to think I'd always be alone
前だけに見据えて ただ夢へ 駆けて
Gazing straight ahead, running solely towards my dream
足跡を見失って
I lost track of my footprints
変わらない 曇天 交わさない 動点
Unchanging overcast sky, uncrossing moving points
「はぐれ山猫」って 笑った
"A stray wildcat," they laughed
音のなかった世界 満ちて 広げていく
A world devoid of sound fills and expands
人たちの声 野生の眼 にかざされて
Sheltered by the voices of people and wild eyes
私は変わりゆく 蕾の lioness
I am changing, a budding lioness
立ってなお 爪を研ぐ 友の前 歩くため
Standing yet sharpening my claws to walk ahead of my friends
真白な獅子は 群れて 群れて 群れを抱く
The pure white lioness herds, herds, and embraces the herd
それが私を 支えてくれるから
Because that supports me
純白の孤高を 追い掛け 寄り添ってくれる モノたち
Things that follow and nestle close to my pure white aloofness
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride.
それこそ私の 誇り
That is my pride
気高いふりして 居場所の線を チョークで 無差別に引いていた
Acting noble, I indiscriminately drew lines of territory with chalk
目指したものだけ 輝くものだけ そして ただ迷うだけ
Only things to aim for, only things to shine, and just hesitating
見失う軌道 不安さの妄動 導いて欲しいって気付いた ある日
Lost orbit, delusional impulse of anxiety, the day I wanted to be guided
融けなかった凍土に やがて 広がって行く 私達の熱 少しずつ 覚えていくから
Our warmth will soon spread across the permafrost as we learn it
もし遠く ずっと遠く離れていても 獅子は 空に向け 咆哮する
Even if we are far, far away, the lioness howls toward the sky
友に声 届けるため
To deliver her voice to her friends
一輪の 獅子は 咲いて 咲いて 咲き咆哮したいのさ
The single lioness wants to bloom, bloom, and howl with pride
萌え出る 瞬間は 見守る人のために
For the sake of those who watch over the moment of budding
百花の王は 一緒に 一緒に 咲き咆哮したいのさ ah
The king of flowers wants to bloom and howl together, ah
we can be the king of beasts, together.
白銀の獅子は 駆けて 駆けて 駆け続けている
The silver lioness runs, runs, and keeps on running
もう不安に 振り返る ことはないから
Because she no longer needs to look back with anxiety
百獣の王は 九十九を信じるから 王なんだ
The king of beasts is a king because she believes in ninety-nine
今なら前だけを この夢だけを見て 走っていられる
Now I can run looking only ahead, only at this dream
後ろに大切な 私達の群れを 纏うのだから
Because I wear our precious herd behind me
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride.
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
孤高は 孤独の裏返しで
Aloofness is the flip side of solitude
ずっと一匹なんだろうって 思ってた
I used to think I'd always be alone
前だけに懸命に ただ夢へ 駆けて
Running solely towards my dream, gazing straight ahead
足跡を見失って
I lost track of my footprints
変わらない 曇天 交わさない 動点
Unchanging overcast sky, uncrossing moving points
「はぐれ山猫」って笑った
"A stray wildcat," they laughed
音のなかった世界 満ちて 広げていく
A world devoid of sound fills and expands
人たちの声 野生の目に かざされて
Sheltered by the voices of people and wild eyes
私は変わりつつある 蕾の lioness
I am changing, a budding lioness
立ってなお爪を研ぐ 友の前 歩くため
Standing yet sharpening my claws to walk ahead of my friends
真白な獅子は 群れて 群れて 群れを抱く
The pure white lioness herds, herds, and embraces the herd
それが私を 支えてくれるから
Because that supports me
純白の孤高を 追い掛け 寄り添ってくれるモノたち
Things that follow and nestle close to my pure white aloofness
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride.
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
気高いふりして 居場所の線を チョークで 無差別に引いていた
Acting noble, I indiscriminately drew lines of territory with chalk
目指したものだけ 輝くものだけ そして ただ迷うだけ
Only things to aim for, only things to shine, and just hesitating
見失う軌道 不安さの妄動 導いて欲しいって気付いたある日
Lost orbit, delusional impulse of anxiety, the day I wanted to be guided
融けなかった凍土に やがて 広がってゆく 私達の熱 少しずつ冷めていくから
Our warmth will soon spread across the permafrost as we learn it
もし遠く ずっと遠く 離れていても 響きさくに向け 咆哮する
Even if we are far, far away, the lioness howls toward the sky
友に声 届けるため
To deliver her voice to her friends
一輪の獅子は 咲いて 咲いて 咲き咆哮したいのさ
The single lioness wants to bloom, bloom, and howl with pride
萌え出る 瞬間は 見守る人のために
For the sake of those who watch over the moment of budding
百花の王は 一緒に 一緒に 咲き咆哮したいのさ ah
The king of flowers wants to bloom and howl together, ah
we can be the king of beasts, together.
白銀の獅子は 駆けて 駆けて 駆け続けている
The silver lioness runs, runs, and keeps on running
もう不安に 振り返る ことはないから
Because she no longer needs to look back with anxiety
百獣の王は 九十九を信じるから 王なのさ
The king of beasts is a king because she believes in ninety-nine
今なら前だけを この夢だけを見て 走っていられる
Now I can run looking only ahead, only at this dream
後ろに大切な 私達の群れを 纏うのだから
Because I wear our precious herd behind me
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride.
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
when you look up at the night sky
what do you see?
the glowing beauty in the twilight
it's no mystery
now watch me set the scene
i'll light it all up
when the time has come
i'll be rising high
longing for me like a lifeline
whenever you see my shine
i'll catch your eye
It's pulling you in
like gravity
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah
Pulling you in
close to me
Watch my glory and might
following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop
The tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
I can be a bright enigma
It's no surprise
But you'll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light
Playing hard to get, but I ain't patient, you'll succumb to my blinding radiance yeah
When you look up at the night sky
What do you see?
My shine! An effulgent sight!
It's pulling you in like gravity
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah
Pulling you in close to me
Watch my glory and might
following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop
The tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
Ooh oh... following me like a high tide
I shine the brightest in the night
the way the waves come nigh
It's pulling you in like gravity
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah
Pulling you in close to me
Watch my glory and might
following me like a high tide
My reign will never stop
The tide begins to rise up to the top
Let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
Follow me... following me like a high tide
mayday, mayday
mayday 声は届いてる?
Mayday, can you hear my voice?
心がズキズキ痛みみたい
My heart aches and throbs like pain.
baby なんて魅力的な見せるテクニックはすぐにクラクラ
Baby, such charming techniques will make you dizzy right away.
mayday それじゃ物足りない すぐにもっともっと欲張るスタイル
Mayday, that's not enough, I want more and more right away.
hey hey もっと焦らしてよ あなたの心に入ってみたいの
Hey hey, tease me more, I want to get inside your heart.
あぁ 見透けた甘い罠
Ah, a transparent sweet trap,
あぁ ハマってあげようか
ah, should I fall for it?
あぁ 自在にコントロールしていたはずなのに
Ah, even though I should have been in total control...
クラクラって酔っちゃいそうなくらい 甘い匂い誘われ
Dizzy, about to get drunk on the sweet scent tempting me,
フラフラって寄っちゃうわ あぁ もう help me...
fluttering and approaching, ah, someone help me...
逃げたいわけじゃなくて これくらいがちょうどいいわ
It's not that I want to run away, this much is just right,
なんてもう君の前じゃ絶対... help meして
and in front of you, absolutely... rescue me!
mayday 舵が取れないの 気持ちがモヤっと晴れないし
Mayday, I'm losing my bearings, my feelings are hazy,
lady なんかじゃいられない 今時のgirlはもう××も××
lady, I can't be like that, a girl nowadays is no longer like that at all.
絶対あるわけないじゃない 絶対にただの勘違い
There's no way that's true, absolutely just a misunderstanding,
論外手の平の上で 踊らされている この感じ
out of the question, dancing on the palm of your hand.
だってもう溶け出すような 体温に魅舞われ
Melting away in body temperature, dancing to it,
なんか変あたまじゃないみたい あぁ もう rescue me...
isn't this a bit weird? Ah, rescue me!
mayday、mayday
Mayday, mayday,
mayday 声は届いている?
are my cries reaching you?
心がズキッと痛みみたい
My heart aches so painfully,
baby なんて魅力的地
baby, what a charming trap.
魅せるテクニックはすぐにクラクラ
The seductive technique makes me dizzy right away.
mayday それじゃ物足りない
Mayday, that's not enough,
すぐにもっともっと欲張るスタイル
I want more and more right away, greedy style.
heyhey もっと焦らせてよ あなたの心に入ってみたいの
Hey hey, make me more anxious, I want to get inside your heart.
ah 見え透いた甘い罠 ah ハマってあげようか
Ah, a transparent sweet trap, ah, shall I fall for it?
ah 自在にコントロールしていたはずなのに
Ah, even though I should have been controlling it freely.
クラクラって酔いちゃいそうな 甘い匂い誘われ
Dizzily getting drunk on the sweet scent, lured in.
フラフラって寄ってきちゃうわ ああ もう help me...
Wobbling over close, ah, help me...
逃れたい訳じゃなくて これくらいがちょうどいいわ
It's not that I want to escape, this much is just right.
なんてもうキミの前じゃ絶対... help meして
But right in front of you, absolutely... please help me.
mayday 舵が取れないの 気持ちがモヤっとハレないし
Mayday, I can't steer, my feelings are murky and won't clear up.
lady なんかじゃいられない 今時のだれも××も××
Lady, I can't stay like that, nowadays nobody...
絶対あるわけないじゃない
There's no way that's absolute (can not believe),
絶対ただの勘違い
absolutely just a misunderstanding (got attracted).
論外 手の平の上で 踊らされているこの感じ
Out of the question, being danced in the palm of your hand.
だってもう溶けだすような 体温に魅舞われて なんか変 あたしじゃないみたい ああ もう rescue me...
Because I'm possessed by a body temperature that melts away, feeling strange, not like myself, ah rescue me...
嫌々って漏れちゃうくらいに あたしを困らせて
Teasing me to the point where reluctant sighs leak out,
なんでもあたしからは絶対... rescue meして もう let meして
From me it's absolute... please rescue me, just let me.
are my eyes deceiving me?
your soul starts to fade
unleash your magic to me now it 's time not to worry
Unleash your magic to me, now it's time not to worry,
do believe in me a journey we have to see
ルリダ・ラリラ インコンプリートメロディ
Rurira rari ra, incomplete melody,
歌い出す sweet, but yet a sad symphony
sung with a sweet, but yet a sad symphony.
unwavering spirit that you told me
how can i do it when you 're not even here? Oh , always me
how can I do it when you're not even here? Always with me.
let out the words i could say to you right now
i can only tell you a bit overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift
that i could never ever trade with anything
let the time send this song to your ears
i hope one day you will sing it to me
versatile melody that i tried to write every day i would pray in my heart
'cause i 'm reach in ' the sky in a time full of worries
'Cause I'm reaching the sky in a time full of worries,
呼んで sing out 夜の記憶 shout out 火は燃える
Call out, sing out memories of the night, shout out, fire burns.
星屑の欠片たちは今願いになる 新たな喜びを願うの
Stardust fragments now become wishes, praying for a new joy.
ルリダ・ラリラ インコンプリートメロディ
Rurira rari ra, incomplete melody,
has been sung in the world so far you can't see
let the wind , let the sea carry this melody
Let the wind, let the sea carry this melody,
legacy , timeless song that carries all the wish i believe
legacy, timeless song that carries all the wish, I believe.
all the words i could say right now i can only tell you a little bit
overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift
that i could never ever trade with anything
let the time send this song to you i hope one day you will sing it to me
ルリダ・ラリラ インコンプリートメロディ
Rurira rari ra, incomplete melody...
are my eyes deceiving me ?
Are my eyes deceiving me?
your soul starts to fade
unleash your magic to me
now it 's time not to worry
Now it's time not to worry.
do believe in me
a journey we have to see
all the words i could say right now , i can only tell you
All the words I could say right now, I can only tell you...
a little bit overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift
that i could never ever trade with anything
let the time send this song to your ears i hope one day you will sing it to me
versatile melody that i tried to write every day i would pray in my heart ,
Versatile melody that I tried to write, every day I would pray in my heart,
cause i 'm reaching the sky
'cause I'm reaching the sky.
in a time full of worries no light i could see do you want me to be here ?
In a time full of worries, no light I could see. Do you want me to be here?
nulling all the emotions you 're supposed to feel even voice i wanna hear
Numbing all the emotions you're supposed to feel, even voice I wanna hear.
shalala shalila incomplete melody arriving in your ears like it 's destiny
Shalala shalila, incomplete melody, arriving in your ears like it's destiny.
rurira rari ra incomplete memory showing all the warmth that i have ever feel
yonde sing out yoru no kioku
shout out hi wa moeru hoshikuzu no kakeratachi wa ima negai ni naru
arata na yorokobi o negau no rurira rari ra a complete melody
has been sung in the world so far you can't see let the wind , let the sea carry this melody
has been sung in the world so far you can't see. Let the wind, let the sea carry this melody.
legacy , timeless song that carry all the wish i believe
Legacy, timeless song that carry all the wish, I believe.
all the words i could say right now , i can only tell you a little bit
All the words I could say right now, I can only tell you a little bit.
overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift that i could never ever trade with anything
let the time send this song to you i hope one day you will sing it to me
versatile melody that i tried to write every day i will sing it aloud , and i will try to shine
Versatile melody that I tried to write, every day I will sing it aloud, and I will try to shine.
常世の闇に囚われたまま 奏でる悲鳴を
Trapped in the everlasting darkness, playing a lament...
聞かせて
Let me hear it.
さぁ 爪を磨いたら
Now, once you've polished your claws,
まだ子供のようなあなたのために
for someone still like a child like you...
あぁ 試されたいなら
Ah, if you want to be tested,
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the everlasting darkness,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
chewing sweet, sweet gum.
いくつもの後悔を
Offering up
捧げて 捧げて
countless regrets, offering them up.
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Basking in a smiling lie,
拒んだままに受け止め上げて
I'll accept you just as you refused.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your lament.
さぁ 指を鳴らしたら
Now, once you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
for someone like a kitten like me...
あぁ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, my throat is parched,
薄紅の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
狭い庭園に閉じ込めたまま
Trapped within a narrow garden,
首輪に繋がれたいの?
do you want to be bound by a collar?
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't take it with some foolish rule,
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
freedom is already in this hand.
愛情では計れない
Unmeasurable by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while you're still weak.
ほら心を開いて
Come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして寝ぼけてるの?
Pretending not to know, are you daydreaming?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せてねぇ
Show me an even hotter darkness, won't you?
さりげない合図に隠れた
Hidden in a casual sign,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Basking in a smiling lie,
拒んだままに受け止め上げて
I'll accept you just as you refused.
常世の闇に刻むこの名を わからせてあげる
Carving this name into the everlasting darkness, I'll make you understand.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
Come on, let me hear your lament.
夢見ないで
Don't dream.
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind,
誰も気付かぬよう
so no one would notice,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
a monochrome world where borders blur.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even adding color, nothing comes into view,
まるで私たちは 息を止めていた
as if we had been holding our breath.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
It's fine now, even far away, I want it to come true.
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
Even though I want to embrace my feelings in this world,
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味は
the meaning of lingering on the canvas of dreams
この胸に 輝いている ストーリー
shines in my heart as this story.
与えることに 意味などないけど
Though there's no meaning in giving,
拾い集めた カケラ 失うの？
will I lose the fragments I gathered?
そして夜は その冷たさを 溶かして手を伸ばした
And at night, I reached out my hand, melting that coldness.
もういいよ 遠くても 届けたい 私は
It's fine now, even far away, I want to reach you.
受け入れてく 涙も抱きしめていたいのに
Even though I want to embrace my tears as I accept them,
夢のキャンバスに 心 込めるのは
what I pour my heart into on the canvas of dreams
この空に 描き出していく ストーリー
is the story being drawn across this sky.
そして夜は その冷たさを 溶かして手を伸ばした
And at night, I reached out my hand, melting that coldness.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私の
It's fine now, even far away, my wish to make it real,
こんな世界 想いも 言葉で包んだ
in this world, wrapping even my feelings in words.
夢のキャンバスに 色足してゆく
Adding color to the canvas of dreams,
この胸に 今 輝いて
shining brightly right now in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 笑いかけてもいい
It's okay not to be strong, it's okay to smile through it.
この心は 永久に羽ばたいて 響くように
So this heart will soar forever and resonate,
塗り替えていく パレット
repainting the palette.
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
Because I'm a star, stellar stellar.
きっと 君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure you had already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
what I drew deep within my heart.
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
This clichéd monologue I'm about to tell you.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ
a wall I couldn't break down.
ふっと 香り立つ朝の匂いが どうしようもなく憎らしくて
The scent of morning wafting up was unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて 震えていた
sitting in the corner of my room, hugging my knees and trembling.
太陽なんて いらないから
I don't need the sunshine, don't want it in my life,
明けないでいて
can dawn please stay away?
その手を伸ばして
Hold your hand out all the way
誰かに届くように
and reach out to make someone feel.
僕だって 君と同じ
We're very alike, indeed, both you and me,
特別なんかじゃないから 明けないで
neither of us is special, so please stay away!
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで
shining as bright as any eye can take.
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
My music will never ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは 待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
What I wanted to be was never a Cinderella who waits forever,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince who goes and gets things done.
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become.
なんてありふれた話なんだ
Yeah, right. A run-of-the-mill story, and that's all,
理想だけ書き連ねていた
in a diary filled with tales so tall.
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
This scene so trivial scribbled in the margins.
きっとあの星も泣いているんだ
I'm sure the stars in the sky are letting tears fall.
明日なんて 来ないままでいて
Can tomorrow never come, can it please stay away?
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way. Reach out and make someone feel.
本当に大切なものは 目に見えないみたいなんだ
The truly important things in life are painfully invisible to the naked eye.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありのまま考えないで
just true to myself, make no mistake.
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
The music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは あえかなヒロインじゃないさ
What I wanted to be was never just a damsel in distress forever,
救いに行くヒーローだ
but a knight in shining armor.
夢見がちなおとぎ話 おとぎ話
It is so fairytale, a total fantasy...
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through this night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで
shining as bright as any eye can take.
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
The music will never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕は愛を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
So I sing now through my love, stellar stellar,
世界宇宙の真ん中で
in the midst of this world and all of space.
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
The music can never, ever be stopped tonight.
そうさ僕がずっとなりたかったのは 待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
What I wanted to be was never a Cinderella who waits forever,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince who goes and gets things done.
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become.
そうだ僕は星だった Stellar Stellar
The shooting star I have been all along, stellar stellar.
Stellar Stellar
はい、ではどうでしたでしょうか？ ゲストコーナーでしたー！
Hi, how was that? That was our guest corner!
今回はね、トワのオリジナル曲とゲストさんのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌う構成にしてみましたー！
This time, we set it up so we'd sing my original songs and our guests' original songs together!
好きな曲を一緒に歌いたいって言ったらみんな快く歌おうって言ってくれて、一緒に歌って踊ることができましたー！
When I asked if we could sing some of my favorite songs together, everyone happily agreed!
特にインドネシア組のムーナとリスタとは初めて一緒に歌って踊ったので、すごく嬉しかったです！
Especially since it was my first time singing and dancing with Moona and Risu from ID, I was so happy!
いろんなワルツっぽい踊りやかっこいい踊りもあって、いっぱい練習して...
There were all kinds of waltz-like dances and cool dances, and we practiced so much...
今日トワってどんだけいっぱいっていうの、やばいって。
Today, I have so much stuff to talk about, it's crazy.
えー、すごいたくさん量を用意しまして
Urm, we prepared a huge amount of stuff,
ええ、しますて
and you know,
あの、こういう形でね、綺麗にすごいできて嬉しいね！
it turned out so cleanly and nicely, I'm so happy!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
ま、あの、ま、いっぱいね、このアルバートいっぱいっていっても今日はねいっぱいに囚われる日なの。ごめん。
Well, you know, there's a lot of things, but today is a day you get completely caught up in it. Sorry.
この、しゃべれなくなってきた。
I'm starting not to be able to talk.
これ、意識するとしゃべれないって。
When I pay attention to it, I can't talk.
まあ、後日ね、感想枠やりたいと思うんで、そこで
Well, I'm planning to do an impressions stream later,
多くの量を、あの、お話ししようと思うので、お楽しみに！
so I'll talk more about it in detail there, look forward to it!
やったー！でわ、
Yay! Well then,
まここからは告知枠になります。
from here on out it's the announcement section.
告知枠へ、告知したいと思います。はい、
I'd like to make the announcements.
いつもの通りグッズを出します！じゃじゃーん！
Right, as usual, we're releasing merchandise. Tada!
ボールチェーン付きアクリルジオラマスタンドと、これらち先生の描き下ろしですね。
Acrylic diorama stand with ball chain, illustrated by Rachi-sensei.
あとはトワ様とお揃いスエットと、あとビビマﾙケースが今回発売されます！いぇーい！
And the matching sweatshirt with Towa-sama, and the Bibimal case are going on sale this time! Yay!
で、このスエットなんだけど、トワね、
Now, about this sweatshirt, you know,
すごいいつもグッズを出すときに考えてるのは、お外にも着ていけて、いける、いける、お外にも着ていけるそんなグッズを出したい！
whenever I release goods, I always think about wanting to release something you can wear outside too.
ということで、こんな感じのおしゃれのセットになりました！いぇーい！
So it became a stylish sweatshirt like this! Yay!
も、トワもね実物はもう見てるんだけど、すごい普段着できるような服なので、みんなね一緒に着てください！
Well, I've already seen the real thing, it's clothes you can easily wear everyday, so everyone please wear it together!
いぇーい！で、
Yay! And,
この3つ全部、あの揃ったものをフルセット買っていただくと、なんと！だだだだーん！
if you buy the full set with all three of these items together, guess what! Tada!
じゃあ、はい！もう
So, yes! This time
今回はみなさんノー喧嘩、何もう、買い逃したとかないです！
everyone, no fighting, no missing out!
トワがね、サインを1枚1枚直筆で書きたいと思うので、
Towa wants to sign every single one by hand,
ぜひぜひフルセット買ってくれたら嬉しいなと思います！はい！
so I'd be really happy if you could buy the full set! Yes!
で、このグッズはねこの配信が終わってから購入できるようになるので、購入してください！はい！
And you'll be able to purchase these goods after this stream ends, so please buy them! Yes!
はい、以上グッズのご紹介でした！単品でもね買えるのでね、いっぱい買ってください！はい！
Yes, that was the introduction of the goods! You can also buy them individually, so please buy lots! Yes!
ま、というわけでね、トワ様トワのソロがすくねぇんじゃねぇかと思ったそこのお店
Well, with that said, for those of you thinking Towa's solo songs are a bit few,
あなた、あなた、あなた、トワ
you, you, you, Towa
この後ね、ラスト頑張っていきたいと思いますので最後まで聞いてってね、よろしくー！
is going to do her best for the last part, so please listen all the way to the end, thanks!
はい、ではソロを歌います！ドーン！ってなんだ、はい。
Yes, then I will sing a solo! Boom! What's that, right.
青い惑星に生まれて
Born on this blue planet,
違う道を歩いて
walking down different paths,
たどり着いたこの街
arriving at this city where
光る粒が弾けた
glowing particles burst forth.
巡る夜にキミと出会い
Meeting you in the revolving night,
いつの間にか手をつないで
before I knew it, our hands met.
笑い声と弾む足で
With laughter and bouncing steps,
どこまでも駆けるミッドナイト
running anywhere in the midnight.
見上げた空星の光
Looking up at the starry sky,
街のネオンが混ざり合って
the city's neon lights blend together.
憂鬱な日々と忘れて
Forgetting the gloomy days,
痛い・辛いとか、苦しい・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
throwing away all the pain, hardship, and darkness.
ボクらもっと自由なはず
We should be much freer.
閉ざした羽を開いたなら
If we open our closed wings,
退屈な日々にさようなら
say goodbye to these tedious days.
夜の街を行こうさあ
Let's go into the night city, come on.
ビルを抜けて
Slipping through the buildings,
街を追い越して
outpacing the city,
さらば青い惑星
farewell, blue planet.
なんて惚けてどこまで行こう
How dazzled shall we go?
変わらないものなど何もないから
Since nothing in this world remains unchanged,
たった一つ 確かな今を刻んで
carve out this one certain present moment.
踊る夜にキミを連れて
Taking you along into the dancing night,
邪魔なものは何もなくて
With nothing in our way at all,
歌う声と軽い足で
With singing voices and light steps,
いつまでも駆けるミッドナイト
Running endlessly through the midnight.
見上げた空 月の光
Looking up at the moonlight in the sky,
街の幻想が惹かれ合って
The city's illusions are drawn together,
退屈な日々を忘れて
Forgetting these tedious days,
痛いとか、苦いはもう全部捨て去って
Throwing away all the pain and bitterness.
見上げた空 星の光
Looking up at the starlight in the sky,
街のネオンが混じり合って
The city's neon lights blending together,
退屈な日々にさようなら
Saying goodbye to these tedious days,
ボクの手を取ってさあ
Take my hand, come on.
だって、私 いつまでもずっと囚われ
After all, I've always been captured forever,
君以外はもうありえない
There's no one for me but you.
ちょっといつもふらふら
Always acting a bit fickle and unsteady,
そっぽ向くの？ 思わせぶり許さないからね
Looking away? I won't forgive your teasing.
好きだって かわいいねって
Saying you love me, calling me cute,
甘やして盲信 あのね 無理だって
Spoiling me into blind faith—hey, "no way," you say,
いけるよって 揺れたって篭絡
Saying "you can do it," swaying me with sweet talk.
ガラスハートを振り回して
Swinging around a glass heart,
骨の髄までしゃぶり尽くして
Sucking me dry to the marrow,
壊れるほど惑わせて
Bewitching me until I break.
you know you know you know
love you 手のひらで転がして
love you, rolling me in the palm of your hand,
彗級銀河を駆け巡って 痺れる声はライメイ
Racing across the galaxy, the numbing voice is Raimei!
勝手な妄想なんだけど
It's just my selfish delusion, but
こっち向いて 君以外はもう愛せない
Look this way, I can't love anyone but you.
きっと気紛れなんだけど いつか私、ヤキモチで狂いそうだから
I'm sure I'm just moody, but someday I'll go crazy with jealousy, so
貢いじゃって イラついちゃって 突き付けたい銃口
Giving everything, getting irritated, the muzzle I want to point at you.
これはサンクコスト？ ただの愛憎？ なんだっていいけど
Is this a sunk cost? Just love and hate? Whatever it is is fine, but
自分ファーストで手懐けて
Taming me by putting yourself first,
ぬくい鳥籠で飼い殺して あざといくらいの笑顔で
Keeping me imprisoned in a warm birdcage with a cunning smile.
you know you know you know
その悪魔で不敵なのに ヤバいキュートな身のこなしが
Even though that devilish look is fearless, your dangerously cute movements
病を患うほど悩殺
Fascinate me to the point of sickness.
気分次第でもっと頂戴 幻だって That's all right
Give me more depending on your mood, even if it's an illusion, that's all right.
ああ、このまま 地獄へと さあ 依存 together
Ah, straight into hell, come on, let's be dependent together.
Low Low Low Low Low...
La La La La...
ガラスハートを振り回して
Swinging around a glass heart,
歌った今すべてが あなた自身の心だって
Everything you've sung until now is your very own heart,
Do you know? You know? You know?
love you 手のひらで転がして 私だけを愛していて
love you, rolling me in the palm of your hand, love only me.
蠱惑的なほど痺れる恋は ライメイ？
Is a love so numbing it's bewitching Raimei?
常闇トワ生誕祭 BIRTHDAY FESTIVAL 2022 TOKOYAMI TOWA
[Tokoyami Towa Birthday Festival 2022]